Guide to the Richard Pommer Papers MC 125
New York University Archives
Richard Pommer Papers
Bulk, 1950-1980
1876-1991
MC 125
New York University Archives
22.0 linear feet
The Pommer Papers contain bibliographic sources used in various publications, pertaining in particular to modern German architecture, the evolution of urban apartment housing, and the architecture critic Lewis Mumford.
Pommer, Richard
Arrangement
Files are arranged topically.
The files are grouped into a single series:
Papers
Scope and Contents
These papers contain the working research files of Richard Pommer, who held the Solow Chair of Architecture at the NYU Institute of Fine Arts. The files contain bibliographic sources used in various publications, pertaining in particular to works on the evolution of urban apartment housing, modern German architecture, and architecture critic Lewis Mumford.
Biography of Richard Pommer
Richard Pommer (1931-1992) was an architectural historian who focused on the Renaissance and Baroque periods. In 1967 he received the Alice Davis Hitchcock Award for his book, 18th Century Architecture in Piedmont. In the 1960s he switched his concentration to modern architecture, particularly that of Germany in the 1920s and 1930s. He was an expert on the architect Ludwig Mies van der Rohe.
Pommer was the Sheldon H. Solow Professor in the History of Architecture at New York University's Institute of Fine Arts from 1988 to 1991. He graduated from Columbia University in 1953 (B.S.) and from NYU's IFA in 1957 (M.A.) and 1961 (Ph.D.). He also taught at Vassar College from 1966-1987.
Access Restrictions
Materials related to personnel, faculty grievances, job searches and all files with information that falls under the University's Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) policy are permanently restricted.
Please contact the University Archivists with specific questions regarding restrictions.
This collection is in
off-site storage
.
Provenance
These materials were transferred to the University Archives by Professor Linda Nochlin of the Institute of Fine Arts.
Le Corbusier, 1887-1965; Mies van der Rohe, Ludwig, 1886-1969; Mumford, Lewis, 1895-1990; New York University. Institute of Fine Arts.; Pommer, Richard; Apartment houses |x History.; Architectural criticism.; Architecture |x Historiography.; Architecture |x Study and teaching |x History.; Architecture |z Germany |x History |y 20th century.; Correspondence.; Documents.; New York (N.Y.); Papers.; Reprints.
- Series I: Papers
  - Art 170, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058535 1
  - Art 272, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Art 271, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Art 271, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Art 272, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Art 272, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Art 270, 71, 72, 1980, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Art 272, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Art 273, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Art 273, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Art 273, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Art 272/3, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ise Gropius Diary, 1924-1926 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Ise Gropius Diary, 1926-1928 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Ise Gropius Diary, inserts, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Pommer, Richard. "Mies and Political Ideology"- notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "Mies and Political Ideology"- correspondance, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Mies biograpy-reviews, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Mies-Nazi materials, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Kutsch, Lothar, "Deutschen Arbeitsfront," dissertation, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Walersch, Margaret, "Schönheit der Abeit," dissertation, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Filler, Martin. "Building and Nothingness." The New York Review of Books, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Frimert, Chup. Schönheit der Arbeit: Produktionsästhetik im Faschismus. Damnitz: München, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Society of Architectual Historians Conference, Abstracts, Papers, Notes, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Kruty, Paul Samuel. "Frank Lloyd Wright and Midway Gardens", 1989 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Kruty dissertation, con't, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Kruty dissertation, con't, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Articles on Ludwig Hilberseimer, "Necropolis" by Pommer, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058536 9
  - Hilberseimer article - correspondence, expenses, 1983-1987 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Hilberseimer article, rough draft, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Hilberseimer article, miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Hilberseimer Papers finding aid, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Hilberseimer - photo inventory and illustrations, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Ostendorfer, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Hilberseimer - Problem, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Hilberseimer buildings, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Der Einzige, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Letters to Hilberseimer, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Hilberseimer - Bauhaus Archives, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Hilberseimer Biography, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Early Projects, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Wohlfahrtsstadt, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Hilberseimer, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Hilberseimer, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Hilberseimer, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - On Hilberseimer, 1919-1928, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Freidrich, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Non-Hilberseimer, 1924-1934 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Hilberseimer - Berliner Archives, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Hilberseimer - Entfaltung, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - GS I, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - GS Bauwelt, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Grossstadt, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - GS 4, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Gesellschaft, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Lewis Mumford Buell articles, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058537 7
  - Mumford to get, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Buildings outline, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Mumford, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Mumford works, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Mumford article - drafts, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Mumford lecture - text, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - About Mumford, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Mumford bibliography, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Mumford bibliography, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Samson, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - "Highway"- Mumford article, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Skyline, 1931-1948 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Skyline, 1949-1963 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Critique of Humanism, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - The Freeman, 1920-1921 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - American Mercury - Mumford articles, 1924-1929 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - New Republic - Mumford articles, 1924-1936 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Mumford, various articles, 1917-1930 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Mumford - various articles, 1930-1954 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Mumford - Correspondence, 1970-1975 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Mumford - Books, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - England - 19th century, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Emerson, Greenough, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - America - 19th century, lectures, 1917, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - "Organic Expression and Architecture" - Egbert, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Geddes, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Spengler, 1926-1939 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Utopia/City - Wells, Mumford, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Buell, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Bauer, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Stein, Clarence, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Wright, Henry, undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Other postwar, undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Machine, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Philosophies der technike, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Twenties literature, history, philosophy, undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Hitchcock, 1927-1948 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Lewis Mumford Collection - Finding Aids, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058539 3
  - Mumford - selected writings, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Mumford - finding aids, notes, correspondence, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Schuyler, articles, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Other critics, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Frank Lloyd Wright - Modern Architecture, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Wright-Mumford correspondence, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - MOMA Exhibit of Modern Architects, correspondence catalog, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - MOMA Archives, notes, correspondence, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Wright-Hitchcock correspondence, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Philip Johnson correspondence, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Bibliography about Germany A-M (in shoebox), undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Bibliography about Germany N-Z (in shoebox), undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - NY State Mental Hospital Construction, 1967-1981 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058540 1
  - Bronx State School, 1967, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Kings County State School - Schematic Plan, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Bronx Developmental Center, 1976-1980 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Schematic Plans, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - NY State Urban Development - Twin Parks/Sunnyside Projects, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Bronx Developmental Center, Notes and Schematic Photos, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Bronx Developmental Center, Notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Bronx Developmental Center, miscellaneous, 1969-1982 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Paul Rudolph - Notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Paul Rudolph - other buildings, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Yale Art and Architecture Building - Notes, correspondence, draft of articles, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Yale Daily News, Notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Paul Rudolph - bibliography, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - New Haven - notes and bibliography, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Yale/Griswold, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Scully, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Paul Rudolph, notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Yale Art and Architecture Building, notes, articles, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Yale Art and Architecture Building, schematic drawings, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Yale Art and Architecture Building, articles, notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Paul Rudolph, articles, notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Paul Rudolph, miscellaneous, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Yale Art and Architecture Building, research notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Studioes, etc. - notes, photos, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - "High Rise Living" - Pommer, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - English apartments, notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Vienna, notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - French apartments, notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Albert Hall - notes, schematic prints and negatives, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - "Parisian Flats" Lecture, undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - New York apartment houses - lecture, undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - "High Rise Living" - draft, notes, correspondence, undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Apartments - notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Hotels - notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - New York City Architecture, 1920s, 1930s (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - American Dwelling Design Project, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058541 9
  - Hubert - Notes, Photos, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Richard Morris Hunt, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Crowninshield House/Richardson - Blueprints, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Hardenbergh/Dakota Stable, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - History of Apartment Buildings - Drafts, bibliographies, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous - Minor Apartments, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 1920s Apartments - notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Literary - Notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - NYC Apartment Houses - Flagg, etc., undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Apartment Houses - New York Public Library, N-YHS Materials, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Apartment Houses - Notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - New York City Apartment Houses - Notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - "Recent Literature on Housing as Architecture" - Pommer, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Columbia University "Housing and Urban Form", undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - "The Architecture of Urban Housing in the United States in the early 1930s" - draft of Pommer (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - "The Architecture of Urban Housing in the United States in the early 1930s" - Pommer (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Committee for the Preservation of Architectual Records, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Anthony Jackson - A Place Called Home - Notes Housing Complexes - Schematic Photos and Negatives, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Pommer "Architecture of Urban Housing" article - correspondence, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Avery - notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - "Recent Literature on Housing as Architecture" - Pommer, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Cornell Library - notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Plan Units for Low-Rent Housing- Articles, Notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Plan Units-Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Questions and Ideas - Notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Sociology and Architecture - Notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Housing for the Elderly - notes, bibliography, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - N.A.H.O- Notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - New York City Tenement Housing - Pre-WWI, undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Stern, Robert - "With Rhetoric: The New York Apartment House"-, undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Garden City - notes, photos, undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - WWI Architecture - notes, articles, finding aids, undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Coverage - notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Government archives - notes, finding aids, undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Public Works Administration - notes, memoranda, undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Housing 1920s and 1930s - Notes, Articles, undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Carl Mackley Houses - correspondence, 1972-1978 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - United States Housing Authority - Strauss Notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - NY City Housing Authority - Notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Housing To Do, undated (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Housing - Notes, periodicals, undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Potter, undated (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Williamsburg Houses - Notes, Schematic Drawings, undated (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Red Hook, undated (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Harlem River Houses - notes, blueprints, undated (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - New York City Housing, 1920-1936 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Eugene Klaber/FHA, undated (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Howe and Lescaze, undated (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Chrystie/Forsyth Housing Development, undated (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Queensbridge, undated (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Farmers Home Administration, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058542 7
  - Division of Defense Housing, 1940s (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Oscar Stonorov - speeches, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Stonorov-Cole materials, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Alfred Kastner, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Carl Mackley - notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Stonorov - notes, biography, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Stonorov - correspondence, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Laramie - notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Laramie - projects, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Stonorov/Haws Architects, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Carl Mackley Houses/Juniata Park Housing Corporation, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Andrew Thomas, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - 14) Camden Labor Housing Conference, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Edelman, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Philadelphia Housing Association, 1924-1937 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Cedar Central Project - photos, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - "Lakeview Terrace:Architecture as Housing" Helen Harrison, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Lakeview Terrace - blueprints, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Weinberg, Teare, Herman Architects, undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Teare, 1977-1979 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Central/Scovill Slum Project, 1931-1932, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Walter McCornack - publications, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Ernest Bohn, 1932-1934 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - "The Development of Public Housing in Cleveland"-Donna Ferguson, undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Carl Feiss, undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Cleveland - notes, bibliographies, undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Adam, 1931 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Emilio Ambasz, undated (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Arts and Crafts, undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Austria, undated (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Alvar Aalto, undated (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Craven, undated (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Raimund Abraham, 1973-1976 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Diana Agrest/Marie Gandelsonas, undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Marcel Breuer, undated (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Boulée, undated (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Butterfeld, undated (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Behne, undated (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Berlage, undated (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Behrendt, undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - De Baudot, undated (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Belgium, undated (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Bötticher, undated (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Behrens, undated (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Behrens, undated (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Behrens - Tall Buildings, undated (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Berlage, undated (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Catalonia, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058543 5
  - Francesca - Le Corbusier, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Le Corbusier, 1930 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Le Corbusier, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Corbusier, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Le Corbusier - 370, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Archive Notes - Esprit Nouveau, SDN, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Le Corbusier - Furniture, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Le Corbusier and De Stijl, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Le Corbusier - educators, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Le Corbusier - Purism, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Le Corbusier - La Chaux-de-Fonds, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Brasilia, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Le Corbusier - Chandigarh, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Le Corbusier - Urbanism, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Le Corbusier - "Deastin de Paris", undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Late Corbusier - Modular, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Le Corbusier - Rudolph, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Le Corbusier, 1920s (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Cubism, undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - "Dutch Architecture Between the Wars"-conference, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Deconstuctivist Architecture, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Design, undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Darmstadt, undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Pommer draft from "Dutch Architecture between the Wars"-colloquim, undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - 18th Century England, undated (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - 19th and 20th Century England, undated (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Eiffel, undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Endell, undated (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Eisenman, undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Josef Frank, undated (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Theodor Fischer, undated (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - France 1920s, undated (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Buckminster Fuller, undated (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - France - 18th Century, undated (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Eisenman, undated (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - France - 19th Century, undated (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Form, undated (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Futurism, undated (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Ferri, undated (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Finland, undated (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Garnier, undated (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - 18th Century Gardens, undated (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Garnier, undated (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Gaudi, undated (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Guadet, undated (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Getty, undated (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Behrens, undated (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Hector Guimard, undated (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Greek Revival, undated (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Gropius, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058544 3
  - Bauhaus - Weimar, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Bauhaus - Dessau, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Märzgefallen, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Gropius, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Gropius - Bauhaus, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Nerdinger, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Graves, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Graves, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Graves, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Graves - Schematic Design Negatives, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Hejduk, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Holabird, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Horta, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Hegel, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Hoffman, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Holland, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Hübsch, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Isosaki, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Italians, undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Pommer - International Style presentation, undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Kahn - housing, undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Jourdain, undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Johnson, undated (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Kandinsky, undated (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Pommer lecture: "Kahn, Mies and the New Museum of Art," Duke University, 1989 Nov. 19 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Jordy, undated (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Metabolists, undated (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Jefferson, undated (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - De Klerk, undated (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Owen Jones, undated (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Kahn, undated (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Loos, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Lutyens, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Ledoux, undated (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Left, undated (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Lescaze, undated (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Lodoli, 1964-1976 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Mackintosh, undated (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Mendelsohn, undated (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Moore, undated (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Morris, undated (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Meier/Westbeth, 1970-1974 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Muthesius, undated (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - New York Skyscrapers, undated (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Naumann, undated (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - 19th Century - General, undated (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - 19th Century Theory of Design, undated (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - New York Articles, undated (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Nietzsche - architecture, undated (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Buell Center - correspondence, minutes, 1989-1992 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Barcode #: 3 1142 04058545 0
  - Books - Library Cards, review of "Architectura Domestica in Gran Bretagna 1890-1939" bibliography, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Committees, correspondence, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Courses, correspondence, descriptions, 1988-1993 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Dissertations - 3 pieces of paper, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Earle, correspondence with Pommer, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Frick, correspondence, lecture topics, 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - IFA Library - Collection Development Committee, correspondence, memoranda, 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Luebbers - resume, article "Jean Furtrieri Prints of the Fourbes " Print Collectors' Newsletter, March - April 1991 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Bruno Paul, correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Modern (Professor of European Art) search - 1991, correspondence, list Pommer's assessment (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Oral Exams, 1991-1992 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Postal, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Qualifying paper, M.A., correspondence, comments, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Rabinow, grant, recommendations, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Rohrer, resume, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Rub, Bel Gedder Theater projects for Chicago World's Fair "Norman Bel Gedder and Theater Design in America " by Rub, 1933, 1989-1991 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Slides, assorted catalogs, undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Olbrich - "Early Works and The Vienna Secession - Early Years", undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Orto, Luisa, dissertation proposal, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Bruegmann, Robert - "Preservation, Restoration, and Conservation", undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Pop - Site/Hardy - Alloway, Lawrence. "Popular Culture and Pop Art." Studio International, July/August 1969, undated (Box 10, Folder 22)